Guide to the Souvenir Performance Program Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Souvenir performance program collection
1840-1950
YCAL MSS 260
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4.63
(9 boxes)
The collection consists of souvenir performance programs, the majority of which document anniversary or other special performances of individual actors, theatrical productions, theatres, and theatrical production companies in the United States and Great Britain.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Yale Drama Library in 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of souvenir performance programs, the majority of which document anniversary or other special performances of individual actors, theatrical productions, theatres, and theatrical production companies in the United States and Great Britain. There are several souvenir programs documenting dance performances and films. Some of the programs are accompanied by additional related brochures, serial issues, broadsides, etc. The program formats include single sheet programs on paper, die-cut paper board, and silk. Multi-page publications include photographs, narrative biographies and histories of individuals, theatres, and plays, and reproductions of sets and costume designs. In addition to the souvenir programs, there are a small number of programs documenting recitals and dramatic readings; school performances; religious dramas; church services and concerts; and miscellaneous meetings, ceremonies, and exhibitions. The majority of the material dates from the late-nineteenth through the mid-twentieth century.
Arrangement
Material is organized into eight series: Actors; Plays; Theatres; Theatre Companies; Dance Performances; Films; Recitals and Amateur Performances; and Ceremonies, Meetings, and Exhibitions.
Actors -- Great Britain; Actors -- United States; Concert programs; Theater programs; Theater -- Great Britain; Theater -- United States; Souvenir programs
- Actors, 1880-1925; Series I; 1.83; (2 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Material is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of programs documenting anniversary, testimonial, benefit, and memorial performances and celebrations of individual actors. City, venue, and date of performance are provided when available, but since souvenir programs were often published for actors on tour to several cities they do not always identify city and venue.
  - Adams, Maude
    - in The Little Minister (2 programs), 1898, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - in Quality Street, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allen, Viola
    - in The Eternal City, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - in In the Palace of the King, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - in Twelfth Night, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bellew, Kyrle; in A Gentleman of France, with portfolio of performance photograph reproductions, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bernhardt, Sarah
    - Catalog of paintings and sculpture by and of Bernhardt, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bernhardt's London Coliseum season, London, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bernhardt's London Coliseum season, London, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Billington, Mrs. John; "Programme of the special performance given by her brother and sister artists on the occasion of her farewell to the stage," Lyceum Theatre, London, 1899 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bingham, Amelia; stock company, Bijou Theatre, New York, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dauvray, Helen; 50th performance of Dauvray in One of Our Girls, Lyceum Theatre, New York, 1885 December 26 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Drew, John; in the one-hundredth performance of The Masked Ball, Standard Theatre, New York, 1992 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Duse, Elenora; American tour, 1902-1903 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Eldridge, Louisa (Aunt Louisa); testimonial, Academy of Music, New York, 1893 April (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Forbes-Robertson, J.; "A Motto for Every Day of the Month" from The Passing of the Third Floor Back (2 copies), 1910 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fiske, Mrs.; in Mary of Magdala, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Gillette, William; in Sherlock Holmes, Garrick Theatre, New York, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hackett, James K.
    - in The Crisis, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - in Don Caesar, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hampden, Walter, "Proem", undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Harned, Virginia; in Alice of Old Vincennes, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Holland, Joseph Jefferson; Testimonial, Metropolitan Opera House, New York, 1905 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Irving, Henry
    - in Becket, Lyceum Theatre, London (two copies), 1893 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - in Dead Heart, Lyceum Theatre, London, 1889 September 28 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - in Eugene Aram; publication entitled: The Henry Irving Dream of Eugene Aram by F. Drummond Niblett (1887) (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - in Faust; publication entitled: The Lyceum "Faust" by Joseph Hatton, [1887?] (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - in King Arthur, Lyceum Theatre, London, 1895 January 12 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - in King Lear, Lyceum Theatre, London, 1892 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - in Macbeth, Lyceum Theatre, London, 1888 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - in Madame Sans-Gêne, Lyceum Theatre, London (two copies), 1897 April 10 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - in Ravenswood, Lyceum Theatre, London, 1890 September 20 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Mackay, John A.; "Remembrance Programme. Testimonial by the co-workers and friends of the late John A. MacKay," New Park Theatre, New York, 1891 April 17 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Proctor, Joseph; "Fiftieth Year of Joseph Proctor's Appearance Upon the Dramatic Stage," and performance in Nick of the Woods, Howard Athenaeum, [Boston], 1883 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Rich, Charles J.; Benefit performance of Oliver Byron in The Inside Track, Howard Athenaeum, Boston, 1885 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Russell, Annie; in A Royal Family, Lyceum Theatre, New York (2 copies), 1900 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sothern, E. H.
    - in Accused, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - in If I Were King, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - in Our American Cousin, Belasco Theatre, Washington D.C., accompanied by pamphlet containing production history of the play, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Thompson, Lydia; "Programme of the special performance given by her brother and sister artists...on the occasion of her farewell to the stage," Lyceum Theatre, London, 1899 May 2 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Toler, Sidney; 100th performance with the Academy Players, Academy of Music, Halifax, 1913 January 15 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Tree, Herbert Beerbohm; "Souvenir of the visit of H. Beerbohm Tree and His Majesty's Theatre company to Berlin," New Royal Opera Theatre, 1907 April (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Vincent, Mrs. J. R.; "Testimonial to Mrs. J. R. Vincent in observance of the Fiftieth Anniversary of her adoption of the stage," Boston Museum, Boston, 1885 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Warren, William; "Testimonial to Mr. William Warren in observance of the Fiftieth Anniversary of his adoption of the stage," Boston Museum, Boston, 1882 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Weber and Fields; "A Pictorial Souvenir", 1901 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Plays, 1883-1950; Series II; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of production.
  This series consists of programs for specific productions, the majority of which document anniversary performances of a production. The city, venue, and date of performance are provided when available.
  - Adonis, 600th performance, Bijou Opera House, New York, 1886 April 15
  - Anne of a Thousand Days, produced by the Playwright's Company, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Ben-Hur, a Klaw and Erlanger production, New York, 1900
  - A Chinese Honeymoon, 500th performance, Strand Theatre, London, 1902 December 29 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - The Common Glory, annual performance at Matoaka Lake Amphitheatre, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1948, 1949, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - The Corsair, 100th consecutive performance, Bijou Opera House, New York, 1888 January 9 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - The County Chairman, 237th performance, memento of the closing night of the season of 1903-1904, Wallack's, New York, 1904 June 4 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - David Garrick, Criterion Theatre, London, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Erminie, 450th representation, Casino, New York, 1887 July 21
  - Evangeline, 200th consecutive performance, 14th St. Theatre, New York, 1886 March 26
  - Evangeline, 250th consecutive performance, 14th St. Theatre, New York, 1886 April 30
  - Evangeline, 1000th performance and complimentary testimonial to Edward E. Rice, Boston Theatre, Boston, 1880 June 30 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - The Freiburg Passion Play, New York Hippodrome, New York, 1929
  - Fresh, the American, with Mr. John T. Raymond, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - The Girl I Left Behind Me, 100th performance, Empire Theatre, New York, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Hamlet, performed by the "leading Players of America in honor of Lester Wallack," Metropolitan Opera House, New York, 1888 May 21 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Hamlet, with "Maurice Evans in his new production", 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Hamlet, Robert Breen's production performed at the Hamlet Festival at Elsinore, Kronborg Castle, Elsinore, Denmark, 1949 June 17-27 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Iolanthe, 100th performance, Bijou Theatre, Boston, 1883 March 3 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Iolanthe, 150th performance, Bijou Theatre, Boston, 1883 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Kismet; magazine issues dedicated to the 1911 production of the play at the Garrick Theatre: The Play Pictorial, Vol. XVIII, no. 106 [1911]; The Playgoer and Society Illustrated, Vol. IV. no. 20 [1911], and L'Illustration Théatrale, No. 232 (1913 Feb 1), 1911-1913 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - A Legal Wreck, 50th performance, Madison Square Theatre, New York, 1888 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - The Little Minister, Theatre Royal, Haymarket, London, 1897 November 6 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Matinée...in aid of the fund for the sufferers from the disaster to the White Star Liner Titanic, London Hippodrome, London, 1912 April 30 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - The Mission Play, Mission Playhouse at the old San Gabriel Mission, California, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Much Ado About Nothing, St. James Theatre, London, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - The Notorious Mrs. Ebbsmith, 50th performance, Royalty Theatre, London, 1901 April 15 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - The Only Way, Lyceum Theatre, London, 1899
  - Peter Ibbetson, "a Matinee in aid of the Allied Forces' Base Hospital," His Majesty's Theatre, London, 1915 July 23
  - Pickwick, Empire Theatre, New York, 1927
  - Pounce & Co., 50th consecutive performance, Bijou Theatre, Boston, 1883 June 1 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - La Poupée, Christmas souvenir, Prince of Wales' Theatre, London, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - The Professor, 350th presentation, Madison Square Theatre Company, Haverly's 14th Street Theatre, New York, 1882 May 17 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - The Rivals, testimonial for C. W. Couldock, Fifth Avenue theatre, New York, 1895 May 31 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - The Rivals, Jefferson-Florence Comedy Company, Arch Street Theatre, Philadelphia, 1889 December 2 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Rose Michel, 100th performance, Union Square Theatre, New York, 1876 February 28 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Sign of the Cross, Lyric Theatre, London, 1896 January 4 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - A Streetcar Named Desire, [Broadway production], New York, [circa 1948] (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - The Whip, The Drury Lane Company of America, Manhattan Opera House, New York, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Yoshe Kalb, Yiddish Art Theatre, New York, [circa 1933] (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Theatres, 1883-1929; Series III; 0.21; (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically by theatre name.
  This series contains programs and other materials relating to openings, closings, anniversaries and other events of specific theatres.
  - Boston Museum, "Final Week May 25th to 30th prior to its demolition sixty second and last season 1902-1903," Boston, 1903 May 25-30 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Drottningholm Theatre, Sweden, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Earl Carroll Theatre, Fioretta, Boston, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Eden Musée, monthly catalogue, New York, 1900 May (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - McKee Rankin's Theatre, souvenir of the opening, Joseph Jefferson performing in Rip Van Winkle, New York, 1883 September 3 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Park Theatre, Boston
    - Fourth anniversary and final performances of Mr. and Mrs. W. J. Florence in An Old Stager; or, that Angel Mac, 1883 April 14 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Sixth anniversary; Union Square Theatre Company in A Prisoner for Life, 1885 April 4 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Park Theatre, Thirteenth anniversary; Richard Mansfield in A Paris Romance, Brooklyn, New York, 1888 February 1 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Stratford Shakespearean Festival, Stratford, Ontario, Canada; souvenir photograph booklet, undated (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Wallack's, closing performance, New York, 1915 May 1 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Ziegfeld Theatre, New York, [1927?] (Box 5, Folder 87)
- Theatre Companies, 1898-1935; Series IV; 0.42; (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of theatre company.
  This series consists of programs and other materials relating to the productions of specific theatre companies.
  - American Shakespeare Foundation; Shakespeare Celebration for the benefit of the American Shakespeare Memorial Fund, Metropolitan Opera House, New York, 1928 January 29 (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Balieff's Chauve-Souris American tour, 1928, undated (Box 6, Folder 89-90)
  - The Civic Repertory Theatre (two different publications), New York, 1933, undated (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Greenwich Village Theatre, invitation to performance of first bill, New York, 1917 Nov 14 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - The Group Theatre, production of Men in White, New York, [1933] (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Jushny's Theater, production of revue The Blue Bird, Cort Theatre, New York, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - The Lambs, The Lambs' Star Gambol Programme, New York, Boston, Springfield, Brooklyn, Philadelphia, Baltimore, Washington, Pittsburgh, Chicago, 1898 May (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Louis Jouvet Compagnie Dramatique Française, American tour sponsored by The American National Theatre and Academy, [circa 1951] (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Mei Lan-Fang and company, Chinese Drama, first American tour, [193?] (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - The Moscow Art Theatre, first American tour; program accompanied by George Pierce Baker's personal copy of The Moscow Art Theatre and Its Distinguishing Characteristics, by A. L. Fovitzky (New York: A. Chernoff Publishing Co., 1922), 1922-23 (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - The Players, New York
    - The Rivals, First Annual Classic Revival, Empire Theatre (two copies), 1922 June (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - The School for Scandal, Second Annual Classic Revival, Lyceum Theatre, 1923 June (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - She Stoops to Conquer, Third Annual Classic Revival, Empire Theatre (two copies), 1924 June (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Trelawny of the "Wells", Fourth Annual Revival, Knickerbocker Theatre (two copies), 1925 June 1 (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - King Henry IV, Fifth Annual Revival, Knickerbocker Theatre (two copies), 1926 May 31 (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Julius Caesar, Sixth Annual Classic Revival, New Amsterdam Theatre, 1927 June 6 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - The Beaux Stratagem, Seventh Annual Classic Revival, Walter Hampden Theatre (two copies), 1928 June 4-9 (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Becky Sharp, Eighth Annual Revival, Knickerbocker Theatre, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Milestones and The Little Father of the Wilderness, Ninth Annual Revival, Empire Theatre, 1930 June 2 (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, Twelfth Annual Revival, Alvin Theatre, 1933 May 29 (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Seven Keys to Baldpate, Thirteenth Annual Revival, National Theatre, 1935 May 27, 1957 January 6 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      General note
      Accompanied by offprint from The Players Bulletin (Winter, 1957), "The Founder's Night Address at the Players" by George Middletown
  - Shakespeare Association of America production of Ethel and Macbeth, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Theatre Guild, production of Back to Methuselah, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - Theatre Guild of Southern California, production of Tonight at 8:30, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 112)
- Dance Performances, 1920-49; Series V; 4
  Arranged alphabetically by name of dance company or performer.
  This series consists of programs for dance performances.
  - The Dionysian Magazine, Vol. no. 1 [1924] containing souvenir program for the forthcoming season (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - Jobs Ballet, Sixth American Tour in 1941/42 (Box 7, Folder 114)
  - Pavlova; three souvenir programs from two American tours, and various playbills from performances in New York and New Haven, Connecticut, [circa 1920] (Box 7, Folder 115)
  - Sadder's Wells Ballet, first American appearance, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 116)
- Films, 1926, 1948; Series VI; 3
  Arranged alphabetically by film title.
  This series consists of programs for motion-picture films.
  - Ben-Hur, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 117)
  - The Red Shoes, [1948] (Box 7, Folder 118)
  - Tell It to the Marines; accompanied by a hand bill for the film from the Embassy Theatre, New York, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 119)
- Recitals and Amateur Performances, 1849-1932; Series VII; 4
  Arranged alphabetically by type of performance.
  This series consists of materials relating to theatrical and musical performances in church, school and amateur venues.
  - Church services and concerts, various New York and New England venues, 1849-1931 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - Dramatic readings and recitals, various New York, New England, and European venues, 1865-1932 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Religious drama, various New York, Boston, Chicago, etc. venues, 1925-1930, undated
  - School and amateur performances held in various U.S. (predominantly Massachusetts) venues, 1896-1932 (Box 8, Folder 122)
- Ceremonies, Meetings and Exhibitions, 1852-1932; Series VIII; 7
  Arranged alphabetically by organization name or subject of event.
  This series consists of programs, announcements, catalogues, brochures, and ephemera documenting a variety of events.
  - Actor's Fund Fair, Madison Square Garden, New York, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - Centennial Souvenir of the Inauguration of George Washington, New York, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Memorial Tribute to Moss Hart, Music Box Theatre, New York, 1962 January 9 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - Miscellaneous meetings and ceremonies held in various New York, Massachusetts, and Connecticut venues, 1875-1928 (Box 8, Folder 126)
  - Royal Institution Soiree, Liverpool, 1852 April 22 (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - Stage design exhibition catalogs, brochures, and publicity materials, including those for exhibitions of the "new stagecraft", 1914-26, undated (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Theatre association and magazine brochures, flyers, etc., including Theatre Arts Magazine, Drama League of America, Equity Players, New York Drama League, and the Independent Theatre Association of America, 1923, 1925, undated (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Twelfth Night Club, Inc., "Golden Jubilee Revel," New York, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - U.S. speech association programs and brochures, 1925-1932 (Box 8, Folder 131)
- Oversize, 0.92; (1 box)
  - Adonis (Series II), 1886 (Box 9, Folder 132)
  - Ben-Hur (Series II), 1900 (Box 9, Folder 133)
  - Erminie (Series II), 1887 July 21 (Box 9, Folder 134)
  - Evangeline (Series II), 1886 March 26 (Box 9, Folder 135)
  - Evangeline (Series II), 1886 April 30 (Box 9, Folder 136)
  - The Freiburg Passion Play (Series II), 1929 (Box 9, Folder 137)
  - The Only Way (Series II), 1899 (Box 9, Folder 138)
  - Peter Ibbetson (Series II), 1915 (Box 9, Folder 139)
  - Pickwick (Series II), 1927 (Box 9, Folder 140)
  - Religious Drama (Series VII), 1925-1930, undated (Box 9, Folder 141)
  - Actor's Fund Fair (Series VIII), 1892 (Box 9, Folder 142)